avery.com 2019-05-19

# Privacy Policy | Avery.com

This is the general privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") for Avery Products Corporation (“Avery”). This Privacy Policy applies to all information Avery collects or acquires from or about consumers, whether online, offline, via mobile and wireless platforms, or otherwise, and whether existing now or in the future, including, without limitation: (i) via Avery.com and other Avery owned or controlled websites and their associated mobile sites, Avery’s mobile apps, and Avery-branded "consumer experience" third party sites (collectively, the “Avery Interactive Network”).

Avery will never sell your personal information.

Avery is committed to respecting your privacy and protecting personal information you share with us. This Privacy Policy describes the types of information Avery may collect from or about you (whether via the Avery Interactive Network or otherwise), the treatment of such information, and the choices you have regarding our collection and use of such information, and your ability to review and update your information. By submitting your information to Avery, you expressly give Avery permission to receive, store, process and use such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy also constitutes part of the Terms of Use that govern your use of the Avery Interactive Network. In addition, this Privacy Policy constitutes part of the terms and conditions (such as official rules) that govern your participation in any and all events and activities offered or sponsored by Avery.

  1. Types of Information We Collect
  2. What We Do With the Information
  3. Information Access & Opt-Out
  4. Protecting Children
  5. Cookies & Similar Technologies
  6. Data Security
  7. Links to Third Party Sites, Services or Products
  8. Changes to Privacy Policy

**Notice to California Residents - Your California Privacy Rights:**

Effective January 1, 2005, under California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (known as the  **"Shine the Light"**  law), if an individual who is a California resident has provided personal information to a business in connection with a business relationship that is primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, and if that business has within the immediately preceding calendar year disclosed such an individual's personal information to a third-party and knows or should have known that such third-party used the information for its own direct marketing purposes, then that business is obligated to disclose in writing to such individual upon request, what personal information was shared and with whom it was shared. A business may comply with this law by: (1) having EITHER a published privacy policy of not sharing a customer's personal information for third-parties' direct marketing use unless the customer has first affirmatively opted in to such sharing OR a published privacy policy of not sharing a customer's personal information for third-parties' direct marketing use if the customer has opted out to prevent his/her personal information from being shared for direct marketing use; AND (2) notifying the customer of his/her right to opt out and providing a cost-free means for the customer to exercise that right.

Any request for a disclosure required under this law should be sent to us via mail to at Avery Products Corp., Attn: CSC/Opt Out, 50 Pointe Drive, Brea, CA 92821. Please note that under this law, Avery is not required to respond to a customer's request more than once in a calendar year, nor is Avery required to respond to any request that is not sent to the email address designated above.

You may also Opt-Out of Marketing Communications from Avery by sending an email to [Opt-Out@avery.com](mailto:Opt-Out@avery.com). Please include the email address of the account and the first and last name of the account owner.  We may contact you for clarifications as part of this process. 

Avery will endeavor to honor your request promptly after receipt.

### 1\. Types of Information We Collect

**Personally Identifiable Information ("PII")**  is any information that can identify or is linked to a specific individual, such as your name, mailing address, telephone number (including mobile number), email address, credit card number, debit card number, bank account number and other financial account information, birth date, gender, occupation, personal interests, demographic, location and household information, etc. To the extent you voluntarily provide your PII to us, we collect such information. For example, as permitted by law, Avery may collect PII from you when you:

  1. purchase one of our products or services, such as when you subscribe to our email contact list;
  2. register to participate in an event sponsored by Avery (such as a contest, sweepstakes, giveaway, promotion, survey, etc.);
  3. enter into a transaction with us, such as ordering a product from Avery through our online store;
  4. use or interact with a product or service of the Avery Interactive Network;
  5. provide or share information using a product or service of the Avery Interactive Network;
  6. send information via message, chat, blog, post or similar functionality using a product or service of the Avery Interactive Network;
  7. create, share or link personal profile using a product or service of the Avery Interactive Network, including linking or associating your profile on a third-party site or platform with your Avery account; and/or
  8. submit a request or inquiry to us via the Avery Interactive Network or otherwise, or
  9. print and save projects using Avery design and print tools (collectively,  **"Identification Activity"** ).

Engaging in an Identification Activity is a voluntary activity on your part. If you elect to engage in an Identification Activity, Avery may ask you for certain PII. Depending on the activity, some of the information Avery asks you to provide may be identified as mandatory and some may be identified as optional. If you do not provide the mandatory information for a particular Identification Activity which requires it, you will not be able to engage in that activity. In addition, if you use the Avery Interactive Network to send information to another person (e.g., a friend, a family member, etc.), Avery will also collect PII of that other person to the extent disclosed by you. 

**Aggregate and Anonymous Information ("AAI")**  is any information that cannot identify or be linked to a specific individual. For example, Avery may collect anonymous group data (demographics, online browsing habits, interests and preferences, etc.) about users of our printing tools and services, users and members of the Avery Interactive Network, etc. (collectively,  **"Users"** ). Avery also collects aggregate traffic data pertaining to the Avery Interactive Network, such as: total page views in a given time period; total impressions; average amount of time that Users spend on the Avery Interactive Network (or a part thereof) each time they visit; average amount of time that Users spend on each page of any one or more parts of the Avery Interactive Network; percentage of Users from a certain geographical area, etc. Moreover, Avery may combine "User Activity Information" (as described below) about you and other Users of the Avery Interactive Network to generate aggregate information that reflects activities, habits, preferences, interests, etc. about our Users as a group. Avery also collects location-based information such as zip code, city and state name. In addition, Avery may take PII and make it non-personally identifiable, such as by aggregating your information with information about other individuals, or by removing personally-identifiable elements (such as names) so as to "anonymize" or "de-personalize" your information.

### 2\. What We Do With the Information

As a general matter, Avery uses information (PII and AAI) collected from and/or about our Users to improve our products and services so that they are appealing to as many people as possible, to administer and maintain operations of the Avery Interactive Network, to offer, market and advertise products and services (including those from third parties outside Avery with whom we do business (collectively,  **"Business Partners"** )) to our Users, to administer and manage transactions and relationships with our Users, to personalize user experiences for our Users, and to build a strong community for our Users.

#### 2.1 Avery's Use of Information

**2.1.1 Transactional, Administrative, and Customer Relation Purposes**

If you provide information to Avery in connection with an Identification Activity, Avery will process and use your information for all purposes related to that activity, including communicating and interacting with you in relation to your activity. For example: (1) if you sign up for a product or service of the Avery Interactive Network, Avery will use your information to set up, administer, service, and communicate with you regarding your account; (2) if you register to enter one of our contests or sweepstakes, Avery will use your information to process your entry and to conduct and administer the contest or sweepstake (including communicating with you in the event you are selected as a winner); (3) if you join one of our mailing or contact lists, Avery will use your information to send you or contact you with information that you have requested or that may be of interest to you; and (4) if you order a product or service from Avery, your information will be used to process and fulfill your order, to communicate with you regarding the same, and to provide customer service to you. Also, if you provide your email address or mailing address to Avery, such address may be used to send you notices of a transactional, administrative or relationship nature or as required by law, such as notification of a material change in this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms of Use for the Avery Interactive Network, notification of an actual or suspected security breach that affects your information stored by or for Avery, public relations announcements, etc.

**2.1.2 Marketing & Advertising Purposes**

**(1) Interest-based advertising on the Avery Interactive Network:**  Avery may use your PII to provide to you interest-based ads (i.e., ads potentially relevant or tailored to your interests) about products and services of Avery and/or our Business Partners. For example, Avery may show ads inside and/or alongside the content you view on Avery.com. Sometimes, these ads are based on the types of products you have purchased or files you have downloaded. However, to make these ads as relevant as possible for you, Avery may infer your interests based on videos you have previously viewed on Avery.com, templates you have downloaded or printed, and may use this information to associate your browser with relevant interest categories and show you ads relevant to your inferred interests. For example, if your prior viewing habits on Avery.com suggest that you are interested in a particular category of products or services, you may see more ads related to that category while on Avery.com.

**(2) Email marketing:**  If you provide your email address or mailing address to Avery (such as by joining one of our mailing lists), such address may be used to send you product and service offers, promotions, and advertisements from Avery and/or from our Business Partners. See Section 3.2 below regarding how to opt out of Avery’s email marketing.

**(3) Mobile marketing:**  Subject to your  _prior opt-in consent_ , Avery may (i) send marketing and advertising messages via SMS (Short Message Service), MMS (Multimedia Message Service), etc., to your mobile device and/or (ii) send marketing and advertising emails to your wireless email account, to inform you about product/service offers, promotions, and advertisements from Avery and/or from our Business Partners. See Section 3.2 below regarding how to opt out of our mobile marketing.

**2.1.3 Market Research Purposes**

Avery may use AAI (including AAI derived from PII) to conduct market research and analysis for ourselves as well as for our Business Partners.

#### 2.2 Disclosure to Third Parties Outside Avery

**2.2.1 Disclosure to our Business Partners**

Except as set forth below, Avery will never knowingly disclose your PII to a third party.

**2.2.2 Disclosure to our Service Providers**

Avery may disclose PII and AAI to our outside vendors and contractors who need to access such information in order to perform services (including, without limitation, transaction/payment processing, order fulfillment, contests and sweepstakes administration and prize fulfillment, data research and analysis, data collection and processing, data storage, data security, hosting and technical support for the Avery Interactive Network, and marketing and advertising support) for us (collectively, "Service Providers"). Avery requires that our Service Providers use your information shared by Avery solely for the purposes of performing services for Avery and that they maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of such information and not further disclose the information to others.

**2.2.3 Disclosure under other circumstances**

Avery may disclose PII and AAI to others if doing so is required by law or, in our good faith belief, is reasonably necessary to: (1) comply with legal process (including a court order or subpoena); (2) cooperate with law enforcement; (3) enforce this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms of Use for the Avery Interactive Network; (4) respond to an emergency; or (5) protect the rights, property or safety of Avery, one or more members of our Users, and/or the public. In addition, Avery may transfer PII and AAI as part of our assets if Avery (or parts of our businesses) are, sold or transferred to, merged with, or acquired by, a third party. Upon such transfer, the privacy policy of the acquiring entity may govern the further use of your information.

**2.2.4 Unrestricted disclosure of AAI**

Given the anonymous, non-personally identifiable nature of AAI, there are no restrictions under this Privacy Policy on how Avery may use, disclose, sell, or otherwise share such information. For example, Avery may freely share Aggregate and Anonymous Information (AAI) with our Business Partners who may use such data for their own marketing, advertising, research, or other business purposes. Avery may also freely share AAI with our Service Providers in order for them to perform services to Avery.

### 3\. Information Access & Opt-Out

#### 3.1 Information Access

If you have an active user account on the Avery Interactive Network, you may access and update your user account information and preferences at any time (subject to the scheduled maintenance of the Avery Interactive Network), by logging into your account and clicking on "My Account" and then changing your preference.

If you do not have an active account on the Avery Interactive Network, or if you have provided your information to Avery offline, you may request to access, delete, update and correct your information as stored by Avery, by sending your request to us at Avery Products Corp., Attn: CSC/Opt Out, 50 Pointe Drive, Brea, CA 92821. Your request will be processed as soon as possible. 

You may request a list of the personally identifiable information Avery has in its records about your account.  To request this list please send an email to from Avery by sending an email to [ShowMeMyData@avery.com](mailto:ShowMeMyData@avery.com). Please include the email address of the account and the first and last name of the account owner.  We may contact you for clarifications as part of this process. 

To request an electronic, machine readable, version of the personally identifiable information that Avery has about your account please send an email to [DownloadMyData@avery.com](mailto:DownloadMyData@avery.com). Please include the email address of the account and the first and last name of the account owner.  We may contact you for clarifications as part of this process. 

#### 3.2 Opt-Out

You can opt out of all our marketing uses (including email marketing, mobile email marketing, and mobile message marketing) of your PII by sending your request via email at Avery Products Corp., Attn: CSC/Opt Out, 50 Pointe Drive, Brea, CA 92821.

You may also Opt-Out of Marketing Communications from Avery by sending an email to [Opt-Out@avery.com](mailto:Opt-Out@avery.com). Please include the email address of the account and the first and last name of the account owner.  We may contact you for clarifications as part of this process. 

Avery will endeavor to honor your request promptly after receipt.

In addition, with respect to certain marketing uses of your PII, you may exercise your opt-out choice through the following alternative methods:

  * Our email / mobile email marketing (i.e., sending marketing emails (including our newsletters) to your Internet email account or your mobile email account):
    * Use the opt-out means (e.g., an "unsubscribe" link) provided in a marketing email that you have previously received from us.
  * Our mobile message marketing (i.e., sending marketing messages via SMS, MMS, etc. to your mobile phone after you have opted in to receive such messages):
    * Reply STOP to a marketing message you have received; OR
    * Text STOP to the short code used for the messaging program from which you wish to opt out (if you have enrolled in multiple messaging programs on the same short code and wish to opt out from all those programs, text STOP ALL to the short code).

**HOWEVER, please note the following:**

For email communications, your opt-out will stop further marketing and promotional emails from us BUT will NOT stop email communications from Avery relating to your Identification Activity, of a transactional, administrative or relationship nature, or as required by law, such as notification of a material change in this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms & Conditions for the Site, notification of an actual or suspected security breach that affects your Personal Information stored by or for Avery, etc.

For telemarketing, your opt-out will stop further marketing calls from Avery but will NOT stop calls from us relating to your Identification Activity of a transactional, administrative or relationship nature, or as required by law, such as notification of a material change in this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms & Conditions for the Site, notification of an actual or suspected security breach that affects your Personal Information stored by or for us, etc.

**Data retention**

Avery will retain your PII for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you products or services, and as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce agreements. AAI and AAI may be retained indefinitely.

To request that Avery erase all of the personally identifiable information it has about your account please send an email to [EraseMyData@avery.com](mailto:EraseMyData@avery.com). Please include the email address of the account and the first and last name of the account owner.  We may contact you for clarifications as part of this process.  **Please note that the erasure of your data is permanent and irreversible.**

### 4\. Protecting Children

Avery takes special care to protect the safety and privacy of children. All products and services of the Avery Interactive Network are intended for general audiences and are NOT directed to children. Avery does not knowingly permit children under age 13 to register on the Avery Interactive Network for any product or Service. Avery does not knowingly collect or solicit Personally Identifiable Information about Users under age 13.

Children under age 13 should always ask their parents or guardians for permission before providing any Personally Identifiable Information to anyone online or through mobile devices. Parents and legal guardians should participate in your child's online and mobile activities and use parental control or other Internet and/or mobile filtering technology to supervise your child's access to the Internet.

### 5\. Cookies & Similar Technology

To improve the user experience on our website and enable you to use certain features in order to show suitable products or conduct market research, some pages of this website use cookies. A cookie is a small text file which is stored automatically on your device. Some of the cookies we use are deleted after you close your browser (“session cookies”). Other cookies are stored in your device and enable us to recognise your browser when you visit us again (“persistent cookies”). Targeting or advertising cookies are used to deliver ads relevant to you on 3rd party apps and websites. By using our site, you agree to us placing these sorts of cookies on your device and accessing them when you visit the site in the future. If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, the “help” section in your browser should provide instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies or see the links below. To check the cookie storage period, you can use the Overview function in the cookie settings of your web browser. You can configure your browser for it to inform you whenever a page uses cookies and decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject the cookies on a given website or generally. Every browser has a different policy for managing cookie settings. The browsers’ policy is described in the Help menu of every browser and explains how you can change your cookie settings.

Useful links for browsers:

  * Internet Explorer: <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>
  * Google Chrome: [https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&hlrm=en](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&hlrm=en)
  * Firefox: <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored>
  * Opera: <https://help.opera.com/en/latest/web-preferences/#cookies>

**Please note that disabling cookies may limit your access to some features of our websites.**

In addition, Avery may use so-called "pixel tags," "web beacons," "web bugs," "clear GIFs," etc. (collectively  **"Web Beacons"** ) to collect AAI about your activities on the Avery Interactive Network. These are small electronic images embedded in web content (including online ads) and email messages and are ordinarily not visible to users. Like cookies, Web Beacons enable Avery to track pages and content (including ads) accessed and viewed by users. Also, when Avery sends HTML-formatted (as opposed to plain text) emails to our Audiences, Web Beacons may be embedded in such emails to allow Avery to monitor readership levels so that Avery can identify aggregate trends and individual usage to provide our Users with more relevant content or offers. Web beacons in emails may recognize activities such as when an email was opened, how many times an email was forwarded, which links in the email were clicked on, etc. Web Beacons cannot be declined when delivered via a regular web page. However, Web Beacons can be refused when delivered via email. If you do not wish to receive Web Beacons via email, you will need to disable HTML images or refuse HTML (select Text only) emails via your email software.

#### 5.1 Use of Cookies & Similar Technologies by Third-Party Advertisers

Avery may use third-party advertising companies including so-called "network advertisers" or "ad networks" (hereinafter collectively as "Third-Party Advertisers") to serve ads and manage ads on the Avery Interactive Network. When you use or interact with a product or service of the Avery Interactive Network, such Third-Party Advertisers may use cookies and Web Beacons to collect AAI about your activities on the Avery Interactive Network and to serve interest-based ads directly to you. For more information regarding the data practices of some of these Third-Party Advertisers and how to opt out of their use of your information, please click [](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Do_Not_Track)[](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/)

#### 5.2 Third Party Functionalities

The Avery Interactive Network contains links to and/or enables certain third-party functionalities to enhance your experience, including, without limitation, social plug-ins, tools and APIs. Prior to using any third-party functionality (e.g., Facebook "Like" button) on the Avery Interactive Network, you should consult the privacy notices of the third-party providers of such functionalities (including Facebook and its Custom Audience Tool), as Avery has no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, such third parties, or how they may use the information. The privacy policies and data practices of such third parties may significantly differ from this Privacy Policy, and Avery makes no representation or warranty whatsoever about their policies and practices. Your communications and interactions with such third parties are solely between you and them, and are at your own risk.

To learn more about how to opt out or change your ad targeting preferences with facebook, visit [https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__www.facebook.com_ads_preferences_&d=DwMGaQ&c=i8WcYkdtj-Ms2X3_u4G0PQ&r=S79t0rdvJgaAKBanH1UCXH8BKMBRd1eDqhiI0EyJvdY&m=NGq5kfRYaNCR5FgJZOURdT-HwpEPMdLEjXQWVCQu1kI&s=cUJi7SMc6NMYrMs3XFAwFbzjWo-8F1TQo3SFlMFatps&e=)

**Use of Google Analytics for web analytics**

For the purpose of website analytics, Avery.com website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC (www.google.com). Google Analytics uses methods such as cookies that enable an analysis of your use of our website. The information collected automatically by cookies is transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the United States. IP anonymization is enabled on this website.  Generally, Google does not associate the anonymised IP address, transmitted from your browser through Google Analytics, with any other data held by Google.

Please keep in mind that when you provide information to Avery on a third-party site or platform (e.g., via a Avery-branded application that operates on a third-party site or platform), information you provide may be separately collected by the third-party site or platform. Information Avery collects is covered by this Privacy Policy and the information a third-party site or platform collects is subject to such third-party site or platform's privacy policies and practices. Privacy choices you have made on a third-party site or platform will not apply to Avery’s use of the information Avery has collected directly through our own sites and platforms, unless Avery’s expressly states otherwise.

**DoubleClick's DART Cookie and Online Tracking and Advertising**

Third-Party Advertisers may use cookies to serve ads on the Avery Interactive Network. In particular, DoubleClick's DART cookie may be used to enable ads through DoubleClick's ad-serving technology. Such cookie is placed on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site that supports ads delivered using DoubleClick's ad-serving technology. This cookie is a "persistent" cookie, meaning that it is saved into the cookie folder on your computer's hard drive and will remain in that folder even after you close your web browser. This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests ("interest-based targeting"). The ads served to you will be based on your previous browsing history. DoubleClick's DART cookie uses "non-personally identifiable information". It does NOT track Personally Identifiable Information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security number, credit card/debit card number, or other financial account information.

To opt-out of DoubleClick's DART cookie and associated "interest-based targeting" advertising, please click [here](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/).

**PLEASE NOTE**  that if you erase or otherwise alter your browser's cookie file (including upgrading certain browsers), you may need to opt out again. PLEASE NOTE also that opting out of the ad-serving cookie does not mean that you will stop seeing pop-up ads or banner ads embedded in websites. You can control many pop-ups by using free software available on the Internet or by disabling JavaScript on your browser.

You may also choose not to receive interest-based advertising from many ad networks, data exchanges, marketing analytics and other service providers by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

If you wish to disable cookies selectively or entirely, you may do so through your individual browser options or using special software. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective web sites. Alternatively you can use the guide [here](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/).

More information on the DoubleClick DART cookie can be found [here](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/).

### 6\. Data Security

Protecting the security of the Personally Identifiable Information that you share with Avery is of the utmost importance to us. All communication via Web Browser between consumers and Avery are encrypted using the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.  All consumer information is stored in a database in a secured environment which is only accessible by key Avery personnel.  Avery utilizes multiple layers of security to protect our consumer data that include firewalls, secure connections, public and private keys and 2 factor authentication.

By providing your email address to Avery (whether on the Avery Interactive Network or otherwise), you acknowledge and agree that Avery may notify you by email in the event of a breach of security involving your Personally Identifiable Information.

Keep your password in a safe place and do not divulge it to anyone. Also, remember to sign off your account and close your browser window when you have finished your visit. This is to ensure that others cannot access your account, especially if you are sharing a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place, such as a library or an Internet cafe.

### 7\. Links to Third Party Sites, Services or Products

The Avery Interactive Network contains links to sites operated and maintained by third-parties, as well as links to products and services (including software) provided by third-parties. For example, the Avery Interactive Network may display third-party ads, and clicking on such ads will take you to the websites of those advertisers. Avery has no control whatsoever over such third-parties, their Internet sites, or their products or services. Once you enter a third-party site, this Privacy Policy will no longer apply, and any information collected from or about you on that third-party site will be governed by the privacy policies and practices of that third party. Third-party sites do not follow our Privacy Policy and their privacy practices may be substantially different from this Privacy Policy. Such third-party sites may send their own cookies to you and may collect data about you and make use of that data in ways that we would not. You access such third-party sites, services or products entirely at your own risk. You should always review and understand the privacy policies and practices for such third-party site, service or product before disclosing any personal information on such site or in exchange for such product or service.

### 8\. Changes to Privacy Policy

From time to time, Avery may change this Privacy Policy in whole or in part, to accommodate new technology, industry practices, regulatory requirements or for other purposes. Avery will provide notice to you if these changes are material and, where required by applicable law, Avery will obtain your consent. If you are a registered user or member of the Avery Interactive Network (e.g., any of our social networking services), Avery may notify you of material changes to this Privacy Policy via email and/or may ask you to affirmatively acknowledge and consent to such changes (e.g., by checking a box or clicking a button) at the time of your next account login on the Avery Interactive Network.

The effective date of this Privacy Policy is May 25, 2018
